Finding Aid for Matthaei Botanical Gardens (University of Michigan) records, 1905-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Matthaei Botanical Gardens (University of Michigan) records
1905-2007
1965-2004
University of Michigan. Matthaei Botanical Gardens.
8728 Bimu C26 2
Established in 1897, the Matthaei Botanical Gardens, with its mission to study and disseminate knowledge of plants as they exist in nature, serves as an educational resource for the university and local community. In 2004 the Botanical Gardens and Nichols Arboretum were joined as a single administrative unit. The records document the Gardens' various organizational, research, and community service activities.
20 linear feet
2 microfilms
3 oversize volumes
5 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was transferred by the Matthaei Botanical Gardens (Donor No. 6701 ) in several accessions, the latest in 2013. 6701
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
collection is open without restriction.
At the time of the founding of the University of Michigan in 1817, administrators provided for the establishment of a "Botanic Garden." However, it was not until 1897 that the gardens were established. At that time, they served as an adjunct of the Department of Botany and the College of Pharmacy, located on the central campus. When this location proved to be inadequate, professors Frederick C. Newcombe and Volney M. Spaulding attempted to obtain a new site.
In 1906, Professor Newcombe successfully secured twenty-seven acres of land, located between Geddes Avenue and the Huron River, from Dr. and Mrs. Walter H. Nichols. In order to enlarge this property, George P. Burns, later the first director of the gardens, acquired twenty-five acres of adjoining property from the city of Ann Arbor and another thirty acres from the Detroit Edison Company.
The new "Botanical Gardens and Arboretum" existed under the jurisdiction of the Department of Botany, of which Director Burns was a staff member. Burns' appointment as director began in 1907 and ended in 1910, at which time he left Ann Arbor to head the Department of Botany at the University of Vermont. After several acting directors, Henry Allan Gleason became director and served from 1915 to 1919.
Dissatisfaction with the Geddes area site arose around 1913, because the land was not flat enough for experimental gardens. President Hutchins reorganized the administration of the gardens by creating a "committee of management," who purchased an additional twenty acres of land in 1914, near Packard Road beyond the city limits. This site later became known as the "Iroquois Site." The Department of Botany and College of Pharmacy utilized this site, while the Departments of Landscape Design and Forestry continued their use of the Geddes site. The latter eventually became the Nichols Arboretum.
Harley Henry Bartlett succeeded Gleason in 1919, and soon President Hutchins once again reorganized the administration of the gardens. The Botanical Gardens became an autonomous department in the College of Literature, Science, and the Arts. Although the Department of Botany was to have no control over gardens policies or budgets, the gardens directorship was to be filled by a faculty member from the department.
The "Iroquois Site" remained the location of the Botanical Gardens through Bartlett's tenure as director, which ended in 1955. Bartlett was succeeded by A. Geoffrey Norman. As the rapidly developing city of Ann Arbor encroached on the site, it became an unsuitable location for the gardens. To remedy the situation in 1957, Mr. and Mrs. Fredrick C. Matthaei gave approximately 250 acres of land near Dixboro, to which the university added an additional 100 acres. The dedication took place on June 14, 1962, and in 1969 the property was renamed the Matthaei Botanical Gardens in honor of the donors.
After the move, several important facilities, such as a conservatory, greenhouses and classrooms, were built through three-phased construction from 1959 to 1965. With the increase in facilities and the expanded availability of natural areas, research and teaching opportunities at the Gardens considerably expanded.
Dr. Warren H. Wagner, Jr. succeeded Dr. Norman as director in 1966, and Professor Erich E. Steiner succeeded Dr. Wagner in 1971. In 1974, during Steiner's tenure, the Gardens' membership program, "Friends of the Matthaei Botanical Gardens," was established. This group, comprised of Ann Arbor area residents, conducts annual fund drives for the gardens. Steiner resigned in 1977 and was replaced by Professor William S. Benninghoff, who had been very active in the development of the Dixboro site. He was later succeeded by Catherine Bach (1985-1987); Anton Reznicek (1987-1989); Erich Steiner (1971-1977, 1989-1991); William S. Benninghoff (1977-1986); Catherine Bach as Acting Director (1986-1987); Anton A. Reznicek (1987-1989); Patricia Hopkinson as Acting Director (1991-1994); James A. Teeri (1994-2002); and Brian J. Klatt as Interim Director (2002-2004).
The Gardens typically have over 30 research projects conducted each year by University of Michigan and non-University of Michigan researchers. In addition, the Gardens provides plant material for U-M courses and is the site for regular classes or field trips for approximately 20 classes from U-M and six other colleges and universities. In addition to research, thousands of visitors come to the Conservatory and grounds each year to participate in adult education courses, volunteer activities, and special events or just to visit the grounds. Two auxiliary organizations that are vital to the success of these programs are the Friends of the Matthaei Botanical Gardens, founded in 1974, and the Docents, who were formally organized in 1982.
In 2003, the associate provost Janet Weiss explored the possibility of combining the Botanical Gardens and the Arboretum. In 2004 the two units were united as a single independent unit of the University of Michigan. In 2007, the Botanical Gardens celebrated its 100 year anniversary. A separate records group for Nichols Arboretum is available at the Bentley Historical Library.
Further information can be found in the Matthaei Botanical Gardens and Nichols Arboretum collection, which covers the records of the units after they combined.
The Matthaei Botanical Gardens records comprise 21 feet of materials spanning the years 1905 to 2007. The records document the Gardens' various organizational and community service activities ranging from administration work to special events for the public. The records have been divided into 11 series: Administrative, Correspondence, Topical, Photographs and Scrapbooks (except for Friends and Docents), Friends of Matthaei Botanical Gardens, Docents, Events, Plans, Projects, Research, and Topical Files. Unfortunately, due to multiple accessions and different processors, these series are not exclusive and researchers are advised to examine the entire finding aid carefully.
Subjects:
Botany.; Gardening.; Horticulture.; University of Michigan. Matthaei Botanical Gardens.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
University of Michigan. Matthaei Botanical Gardens--Maps.Maps.; University of Michigan. Matthaei Botanical Gardens.
Genre Terms:
College publications.
- Administrative
  The Administrative series, 1910-2001 (5 linear feet), is arranged alphabetically and primarily consists of reports and memoranda. The background folder contains informative documents that explain the purpose, organization, and history of the Botanical Gardens. Annual reports and Committees are the largest subseries. The annual reports are yearly accounts of collection development and research projects at the gardens. The Committees subseries contains incomplete records of four committees: Ad Hoc Study, Budget Review, Executive, and Literature, Science, and the Arts Program Evaluation. The Executive Committee records are the most comprehensive, consisting of minutes, reports, and memoranda from the years 1913-1919 and 1980-1986. Though less comprehensive, the other committee records provide insight into the gardens' administration at specific points in time. Also included in the Administrative series are materials on budget, grants, planning and scheduling including the master plan for the years 1980-1985. Docent guides and documents concerning conservatory renovation are also included. The series continues in Box 11.
  - 1910-2001
    - Background (Box 1)
    - Accession Books, 1916-159 (Box 1)
      (2 rolls microfilm, security copy, stored separately [Cold Room 13-6 BD-Bj Bimu C262])
    - Activities and Development (report), 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Aleutian Expedition, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Appointments, salary increases, resignations, etc., 1911-1927 (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports
      - 1910-1918 (Box 1)
      - 1975 (Box 1)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1)
      - 1979, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1980 (Box 1)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
      - 1985-1999 (Box 1)
    - Appropriations and finance, 1916-1926 (Box 1)
    - Benninghoff, William S.-Resume (Box 1)
    - Budget, 1930-1940 (Box 1)
    - Budget-Administrators' Reports
      - July 1982-March 1986 (Box 1)
      - July 1986-October 1988 (Box 1)
    - Budget Review, 1980
      - Correspondence (Box 1)
      - Data (Box 1)
      - Drafts (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Rebuttal to Report (Box 1)
      - Report (Box 1)
    - Budget Review, 1981; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Committees
      - Ad Hoc Study Committee, 1954 (Box 1)
        (report)
      - Budget Review Committee, 1982 (Box 1)
      - Executive Committee
        - Agendas, 1973-1986 (Box 1)
          (incomplete)
        - Memoranda
          - 1973-1979 (Box 1)
          - 1980-1986, 7 folders (Box 1)
        - Minutes and Reports
          - 1913-1918 (Box 1)
            (incomplete, includes administrative committee materials)
          - 1980-1986, 7 folders (Box 1)
        - Miscellaneous, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
      - Literature, Science, and the Arts, Program Evaluation Committee presentation, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Conference on University and College-Affiliated Gardens and Arboreta, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Conservatory Renovation, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Conservatory Visitor Survey, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Deans and Administrative Officers Communications, 1928-1953 (Box 1)
    - Draft (military), 1944 (Box 1)
    - Conservatory Visitor Survey, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Deans and Administrative Officers Communications, 1928-1953 (Box 1)
    - Draft (military), 1944 (Box 1)
    - Easement Agreement-Matthaei Farm Condominium Association, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Employee List, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Employment of Minors, 1942-1949 (Box 2)
    - Endangered Species (Box 2)
    - Endowment Fund, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
    - External Review, 1979 (Box 2)
    - External Review, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
    - Fleming Creek Advisory Panel, 1991; 1998 (Box 2)
    - Flower and Garden Show, 1990-1998 (Box 2)
    - Gift Shop Procedures and Revenue Sheets, 1986-1987; undated (Box 2)
    - Grants
      - 1982-Institute of Museum Services-General Operating Support (Box 2)
      - 1986-Institute of Museum Services-Conservation Project Support (Box 2)
      - Grant Opportunities (Box 2)
    - Horticulture Therapy Program
      - General, 1976-1984 (Box 2)
      - Herrick Foundation, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Labor Reports, 1913-1915 (Box 2)
    - Market Analysis Study Proposal, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Master Plan, 1980-1999; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Membership
      - Minutes, 1990-1996 (Box 2)
      - Rosters, Agendas and Year-Ends, 1990-1996 (Box 2)
    - Memoranda, Intra-University, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Memoranda and letters, 1980-1998 (Box 2)
    - Memoranda for the Record (by the director), 1977-1985 (Box 2)
    - Mission Statement 1991 (proposed) and undated (Box 3)
    - Newsletter, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
      (logo, printing arrangements, etc.)
    - Policies on tours, photographers, etc., 1976; 1990; undated (Box 3)
    - Proposal with Exhibit Museum of Natural History A World Class Cultural Institution, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Purchases
      - Invoice for plants, 1908 (Box 3)
      - Lists of outstanding orders for UM account, 1965 (Box 3)
    - "Recent Developments,", 1986 (Box 3)
    - Report to the Vice-President for Research (Box 3)
    - Research
      - Materials, 1958-1964 (Box 3)
      - Activities and Opportunities, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
      - Reports, 1978 (Box 3)
      - Research and Development Fund, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Retirements (staff), 1946-1947 (Box 3)
    - Staff Meetings, 1992-1993
      (agenda and minutes)
      - Front Staff / Supervisory Meetings (Box 3)
      - All Staff Meetings (Box 3)
      - Public Staff Meetings (Box 3)
    - Staff Questionnaire, undated (Box 3)
    - Vice President For Research (report), 1983 (Box 3)
    - Weekly Schedule of Events, 1984-1987; 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Web Site development and hard copies, 1997 (Box 3)
  - 1954-2004
    - AABGA (American Association of Botanical Gardens and Arboreta), 1982 (Box 11)
    - Academic Year Report, 1977-1978 (Box 11)
    - Accounts, 1992-1993 (Box 11)
    - Accounts -- Closed, 1961-1965 (Box 11)
    - Advisory Board, 1993-1999 (Box 11)
    - Advisory Committee, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Advisory Council, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Advisory Council Meeting, 1999 (Box 11)
    - Alden Dow Transfer, 2004 (Box 11)
    - Allocation of Revenues, 1993 (Box 11)
    - Annual Fund, 1998-2002 (Box 11)
    - Annual Report Materials, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - Board and Council Members, 2003-2005 (Box 11)
    - Botanical Gardens Outlook, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Brainstorming Committee, 1987 (Box 11)
    - Budget, 1980-1988; 1991 (Box 11)
    - Budget Cuts, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - Budget Report (Box 11)
    - Buildings -- Phase 3, 1966-1970 (Box 11)
    - Business Plan for Garden Admissions, 1993 (Box 11)
    - Chronological File, 1986-1991; 6 folders (Box 11)
    - Collection Policy, 1998 (Box 11)
    - Conservatory Long-Range Planning, 1985-1987 (Box 11)
    - Development, 1992; 1997 (Box 11)
    - Discontinuance of the Department of Geography, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Docents, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Donations, 1992-1993 (Box 11)
    - EMU Relations, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Executive Committee, 1968-1975 (Box 11)
    - External Review, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
    - Faculty Committee, 1990-1992 (Box 11)
    - Front Staff Meetings, 1987-1989 (Box 11)
    - Garden Comments (Box 11)
    - General Information (Box 11)
    - Gift Forms, 1997-1999 (Box 11)
    - Greenhouse Rental (Box 11)
    - Guide to Future Development, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Interview Reports (Box 12)
    - Invoices, 1993-1994 (Box 12)
    - IMLS Internship Report, 1998-1999 (Box 12)
    - Long-Range Planning, 1980-1994 (Box 12)
    - LSA Key Administrators, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Master Plan, 1996; 1998; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Master Plan Presentation, 1999 (Box 12)
    - Memos, 1997-1999 (Box 12)
    - Mount Hope Nurseries, 1908 (Box 12)
    - Murphy, Barb, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
    - NADH Committee, 1982 (Box 12)
    - National Science Foundation, 1958-1963 (Box 12)
    - Native Plant Conservation Initiative Grant, 2004 (Box 12)
    - Organization Reports, 1992-1994 (Box 12)
    - Programs, 1954 (Box 12)
    - Rates, 1980-1981 (Box 12)
    - Room Designs, 1963 (Box 12)
    - Room Rental Policies, 1996 (Box 12)
    - School of Information Reports, 2002 (Box 12)
    - Sculpture Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 12)
    - Self-Assessment and Report, 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - Staff List, 1990-1996 (Box 12)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1991-1996 (Box 12)
    - Staff Meetings, 1981; 1990-1997; 7 folders (Box 12)
    - Staff Memos (Box 12)
    - Staff Salary, 1992-1993 (Box 12)
    - Staff Training, 1996 (Box 12)
    - Strategic Planning, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Structure and Glazing Evaluation Report, 2001 (Box 12)
    - Tour Guide for TA's, 1974; 1979 (Box 12)
    - Visitor Policies (Box 12)
    - Volunteer Policies (Box 12)
    - Wagner, Warren, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Wastewater Treatment, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
    - Water Supply, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Yocum, Charlie Meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 12)
- Correspondence, 1911-2002
  The Correspondence series, 1911-1987 (3 linear feet), is arranged into two subseries: General and Topical. The General subseries is arranged first by year and then alphabetically within each year. The Topical subseries is arranged alphabetically. The correspondence are comprised of both incoming and outgoing letters, the latter written by the director and various employees of the gardens. The letters are quite informative and are an important source for studying the evolution and growth of the gardens and its relationship to other major botanical gardens around the country. The continuation of this series, beginning in Box 12, is organized alphabetically.
  - 1911-1987
    - General
      - 1911-1929, 13 folders (Box 3)
      - 1930-1943, 12 folders (Box 3)
      - 1956-1961, 4 folders (Box 3)
      - 1961-1964, 6 folders (Box 4)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 4)
      - 1967-1983, 4 folders (Box 4)
      - 1984-1986, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Topical
      - Administrative Matters, 1955-1960 (Box 4)
      - Alumni Association, 1979 (Box 4)
      - Anthony, Margery, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Arboretum, 1911-1960; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Assistant Gardener, 1911-19 (Box 4)
      - Benninghoff, William S., 1975 (Box 4)
      - Benninghoff, William S., 1977-1986; 4 folders (Box 4)
      - Botanical Garden Development
        - (intra-university), 1957-1959 (Box 4)
        - (intra-university), 1960-1966 (Box 4)
      - Buildings and Grounds, 1914-1923 (Box 4)
      - Burton, M. L. (University of Michigan president), 1920-1923 (Box 4)
      - Clover, Elzada, 1946 (Box 4)
      - College and University Matters, 1974-1977 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence with Other Gardens
        - Arnold Arboretum, Harvard, 1981-1984 (Box 5)
        - Berkeley Gardens, 1985 (Box 5)
        - Botanical Garden, University of California, Berkeley, 1970-1981 (Box 5)
        - Brooklyn Botanical Garden, 1972-1979 (Box 5)
        - Canberra Botanical Garden, Australia, 1973 (Box 5)
        - Devonian Botanical Garden, Alberta, Canada, 1978-1981 (Box 5)
        - George Landis Arboretum, Esperance, New York, 1969 (Box 5)
        - Hayes Regional Arboretum, Richmond, Indiana, 1972 (Box 5)
        - Jardin Botanico, Universidad de Puerto Rico-San Juan, 1979 (Box 5)
        - Los Angeles State and County Arboretum, 1969-1972 (Box 5)
        - Lyon Arboretum, University of Hawaii, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
        - Michigan Arboretum, Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, MI, 1968 (Box 5)
        - Missouri Botanical Garden, 1972-1985 (Box 5)
        - National Arboretum, Washington, DC, 1972-1986 (Box 5)
        - New York Botanical Garden, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
        - Norfolk Botanical Garden, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
        - R.S. Barnwell Memorial Garden, Shreveport, LA, 1972 (Box 5)
        - Strybing Arboretum, San Francisco, CA, 1973 (Box 5)
      - Dale, E. E., 1931-38 (Box 5)
      - Davis, Bradley, 1950 (Box 5)
      - Dean of Literature, Science and the Arts, 1981-1983 (Box 5)
      - Director, Selection of New, 1964 (Box 5)
      - Domino Farms, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
      - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan, 1982 (Box 5)
      - Erlanson, Eileen W., 1931-1932 (Box 5)
      - External Business, 1974-1977 (Box 5)
      - Feinberg, E. E., 1962-1963 (Box 5)
      - Flook, Lyman R., 1915-16 (Box 5)
      - Gentry, Howard, 1945-1946 (Box 5)
      - Gifts (from other institutions), 1933-1941 (Box 5)
      - Greenhouse Supervisor, 1984-1987 (Box 5)
      - Hutchins, H. B., 1913-1914 (Box 5)
      - Interactions With Other Units, 1977-1982 (Box 5)
      - Internal, 1974-1977 (Box 5)
      - International Seed Exchange, 1963 (Box 5)
      - Janaki-Ammal, E. K., 1931 (Box 5)
      - Kaufman, Peter, 1957-1959 (Box 5)
      - Kraemer, Henry B., 1919-1920 (Box 5)
      - Letters of Appreciation (to others), 1979-1986 (Box 5)
      - Lobby Renovation, 1991 (Box 5)
      - Macfarlane, Eileen W., 1950-1956 (Box 5)
      - Materials and Supplies
        - 1956-1961 (Box 5)
        - 1956-1966, bulk 1962-1964; 3 folders (Box 5)
          (arranged by correspondent name)
      - Matthaei, Fred C. Jr., 1981-1986 (Box 5)
      - Personnel, 1956-1961 (Box 5)
      - Plants
        - Campus use of Plants, 1919-1926 (Box 5)
        - Class use of Plants, 1910-1961; 2 folders (Box 5)
        - Introductions, 1935-1940 (Box 5)
        - Medicinal Plants (early years), undated (Box 5)
        - Non-Professional, 1933-1940 (Box 5)
        - Orchids, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
        - Orders, Questions, etc., 1925-36 (Box 6)
        - Plants required for Plant Physiology, 1928-1953 (Box 6)
        - Plants Sent To Other Institutions, 1929-1961 (Box 6)
        - Requests for Plants
          - 1934-1955 (Box 6)
          - 1972 (Box 6)
        - Seeds, 1930-1946 (Box 6)
          (special requests)
        - Species, 1914-1927; 13 folders (Box 6)
          (folders arranged alphabetically by plant name)
      - Purchasing Department, 1921-1926 (Box 6)
      - Reid, John R., 1961-1962 (Box 6)
      - Research Directions, 1938-1945 (Box 6)
      - Rousseau, Jacques, 1955 (Box 6)
      - Santos, Jose Vera, 1943 (Box 6)
      - Smith, Shirley W., 1910-1927 (Box 6)
      - Visitors, 1958-1964 (Box 6)
  - 1957-2002
    - Adult Education Course, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Barnes, Burton V., 1984 (Box 12)
    - Benninghoff, Anne (Box 12)
    - Benninghoff, William, 1978-1983 (Box 12)
    - Black, Margaret, 1996 (Box 12)
    - Development, 1957-1965; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Development, 1957-1965; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Directorship Funds, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Frye, Billy E., 1985 (Box 13)
    - Gardens, 1967-2002 (Box 13)
    - General, 1957-1965; 1984; 1986-2002; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Genetics Garden, 1963-1964 (Box 13)
    - Highkin, Harry, 1963-1964 (Box 13)
    - Hopkinson, Patricia, 1988-1989; 1991-1993 (Box 13)
    - Huston, Michael A., 1984 (Box 13)
    - JJR Inc., 1997 (Box 13)
    - Longnecker, Helene and William, 1993-1999 (Box 13)
    - MacFarlane, Eileen, 1946-1951; 1955-1957; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Mackinac Maples, 2002 (Box 13)
    - Martin, Michael M., 1983 (Box 13)
    - Murray, Betty Jean, 1981 (Box 13)
    - Norman, A.G., 1963-1966; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Palmer, Jeffrey, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
    - Pearson, Paul, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
    - Pollack, Henry N., 1984 (Box 13)
    - Staff, 1990-1992 (Box 13)
    - Steiner, Erich, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Synoptic Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 13)
    - Teeri, James, 1995 (Box 13)
    - Vandermeer, John, 1979; 1981; 1985 (Box 13)
    - Wagner, W., 1966-1967 (Box 13)
    - Wells, James, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series, 1907-2003 (3.3 linear feet), is arranged alphabetically. The researcher interested in architecture will find blueprints of buildings and grounds from the years 1914-1920 and 1959-1965. Topics represented in this series include research, education and employment, garden collections and inventory, public programs, and special events. There is material concerning Fleming Creek, which runs through the present day site of the Matthaei Botanical Gardens and is a tributary of the Huron River. These include memoranda, a summary of creek fauna, and information and reports from the Huron River Watershed Council concerning the roadway design of highway M-14 and its effects on the creek. The newspaper clippings offer information on the operation of the gardens from 1950 to 1972. Researchers interested in the gardens' history will find information on the adoption of the Dixboro Site. The series continues in Box 17.
  - 1914-2002
    - Adult Education Courses, 1983-1986 (Box 6)
    - American Society of Pharmacognosy Meeting, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Articles, 1943-1982 (Box 6)
    - Background (Box 6)
    - Benninghoff, Dr. W. S., 1986 (Box 6)